<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Dewar Writing</title>
    <link>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Daniel Dewar Writing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 09:48:52 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Reflection: 2018</title>
      <link>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/20181225-annual-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 09:48:52 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/20181225-annual-reflection/</guid>
      <description>2018 was a year that took its time coming to an end. The hardest ones always do.
What follows is a reflection of how I feel now that it has ended. There was a lot to process and turn over. Reviewing emails, Slack and social media posts to try and find evidence of how and when my thinking changed on certain topics and what that meant for the business and my own personal growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nine Inch Nails Live: Noise as activism</title>
      <link>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/20181104-nine-inch-nails-american-institutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 09:48:52 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/20181104-nine-inch-nails-american-institutions/</guid>
      <description>Nine Inch Nails rolled into Radio City Music Hall as part of the Cold Black and Infinite Tour.
The stage and light design more subdued by design, Trent Reznor and co delivered a tight, punchy set with lined an unbearable intensity (&amp;ldquo;My message to friends after 4 songs simply read, &amp;lsquo;Holy Fuck&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;). A minimal Nine Inch Nails light show is still more thought-out and overwhelming than 99% of other artists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 2018 Media Consumption</title>
      <link>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/20181103-october-2018-media-consumption/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 09:48:52 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/20181103-october-2018-media-consumption/</guid>
      <description>Media consumed in October is finalized. You can view here.
Quick notes:
Unforgiven
A terribly sad repositioning of the American West mythology and a clear-headed meditation on the unspeakable violence, racist and misogynist culture that sat at the heart of the American frontier.
Eastwood has become a politically polarizing figure and his films are co-opted or rejected through politically narrow readings.
While playing hyper-masculine, hyper-violent characters, Eastwood has also chipped away—in front of the camera and behind—at the empty symbols and rhetoric those characters represent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Depression in America &amp; Twitter Account Deactivation</title>
      <link>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/20181030-depression-america-self-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 09:48:52 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/20181030-depression-america-self-care/</guid>
      <description>I was first diagnosed with depression in 2015. At the time I was undergoing cognitive behavioral therapy to treat a chronic anxiety disorder (fear of catastrophe).
My family has a long history of depression, some members were treated, others were not but the symptoms were recognizable. It&amp;rsquo;s part of my genetic makeup that my body struggles to chemically balance itself.
It requires medication to achieve that balance as part of a wider treatment plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Institutional Racism and Royalty Distribution — A Quick Word on the Music Modernization Act</title>
      <link>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/quick-word-on-music-modernization-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 09:48:52 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/quick-word-on-music-modernization-act/</guid>
      <description>The music industry&amp;rsquo;s shift from physical to digital revenue—and big data—has compounded inefficiencies in licensing, rights owner identification, and royalty distribution.
A proxy example of this is the &amp;ldquo;author unknown&amp;rdquo; filings to the US Copyright Office using the Notice of Intention (NOI) compulsory license under Section 115 of the United States Copyright Act. If these filings are to be taken at face value, there are over 60 million instances where digital service providers are unable to identify the copyright owners of the works in question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on 2017 — First Year as a Founder</title>
      <link>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/2017-founder-startup-year-review-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 09:48:52 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/2017-founder-startup-year-review-/</guid>
      <description>The core seed idea of Paperchain came into conscious thought around May/June 2016. I wrote my first public words on it in July 2016. Rahul joined as co-founder in December 2016.
At the time I was still working full-time. The response to Paperchain was enough to push me to leave my full-time job.
In January 2017 I arranged with my employer for a 6-month phase out: 3 months at 4 days a week, 3 months at 3 days a week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salsa Dancing Naked: Body Positivity as Resistance and Thinking About How to Grow a Diverse a Startup</title>
      <link>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/black-queer-body-positivity-as-resistance-diverse-startup-hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 09:48:52 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/black-queer-body-positivity-as-resistance-diverse-startup-hiring/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I had the privilege of attending the latest lecture from The Polis Project&amp;rsquo;s Dissent In Dangerous Times Series.
The program is run by the inspiring Suchitra Vijayan and I encourage anybody in NYC to attend the lectures.
The speaker on this night was Stephen Thrasher, a Senior Columnist at The Guardian and research in American Studies at NYU. An embed of the recorded lecture is at the bottom of this page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The perfect description of blockchain technology — why it&#39;s becoming more simple</title>
      <link>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/a-perfect-description-of-blockchain-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 09:48:52 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/a-perfect-description-of-blockchain-technology/</guid>
      <description>“Blockchain is a technology that allows natively digital transfer of value.”
 That line was buried in a Medium post by Karl Kreder, cofounder of Gridplus.io.
The more I read it the more I think it’s the best concise description of blockchain technology. The branding problem blockchain has always had is how to describe it in 25 words or less.
Not that being able to describe in such a limitation proves any value of what is being described, however it sure makes it easier to explain at networking events where you may need to offer a description over and over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing crypto tokens in light of the SEC announcement</title>
      <link>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/designing-crypto-tokens-in-light-of-sec-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 09:48:52 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/designing-crypto-tokens-in-light-of-sec-announcement/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this week the Securities and Exchange Commission handed down its ruling on crypto tokens as potential securities.
The investigation was prompted after the DAO “hack” that saw $55 million redirected by a rogue party in the DAO network.
In the specific instance of the DAO, the SEC found that the tokens were offered as securities, and therefore fell under regular securities laws. Applied to other tokens or ICOs, this would mean that coin offerings would be subject to SEC regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Founder Paralysis: An irrational (or rational) fear</title>
      <link>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/founder-paralysis-a-moment-of-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 09:48:52 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/founder-paralysis-a-moment-of-fear/</guid>
      <description>Two days before I was due to fly to Liége to take part in the Wallifornia MusicTech Acceleration &amp;amp; Invest program, I was paralysed by an irrational—or rational—fear.
I was unable to get out of bed. For an extended time there was not enough energy or will to get up.
The night before I suffered through two terrible dreams.
The first was quite long but repetitive. I was meeting many people for the first time, and each time, they picked at me for not sharing more about myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sydney to Liége</title>
      <link>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/sydney-to-liege/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 09:48:52 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/sydney-to-liege/</guid>
      <description>Sydney Airport.
Abu Dhabi Airport.
Brussels Airport.
(wrong train)
Mechelen.
(turn around)
Eppegem.
Weerde.
Vilvoorde.
Schaerbeek.
Brussels-Nord.
Brussels Airport.
(right train)
Leuven.
Liége-Guillemins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A First-Time Founder&#39;s Notes on Finding the Ideal Co-Founder</title>
      <link>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/finding-the-ideal-co-founder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 09:48:52 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/finding-the-ideal-co-founder/</guid>
      <description>I can only say I feel extremely lucky in finding Paperchain&amp;rsquo;s co-founder, Rahul.
I started fleshing out the idea for Paperchain in July 2016. All I had was knowledge of the problem—and as I&amp;rsquo;ve learned further, inadequate knowledge of the problem—and an idea on how it could be solved.
That was the genesis of Paperchain. I knew the industry had trouble identifying rights owners and I knew disparate databases was a driving cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Recommended Reading List for Founders</title>
      <link>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/founder-recommended-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 09:48:52 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/founder-recommended-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>The list below are titles that have been invaluable to my growth as a founder. They are mostly fictional.
They are not books that will teach you sales frameworks, iteration methodology or operational structures.
These are books that have shaped the foundation of my understanding of the world, which becomes the core of how I value my business and my involvement in it.
They are works that evoke the soul of the world and its peoples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Very Easy Death</title>
      <link>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/a-very-easy-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 02:12:05 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writing.daniel-dewar.com/post/a-very-easy-death/</guid>
      <description>There is no such thing as a natural death: nothing that happens to a man is ever natural, since his presence calls the world into question. All men must die: but for every man his death is an accident and, even if he knows it and consents to it, an unjustifiable violation.
 I have thought about death for as long as I can remember. Not dying. Death. I have no desire to die although one day I will.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>